Ilya Biin Senior DevOps Engineer



Ilya has more than a decade's worth of experience working as a system architect, a Go/Python developer, and DevOps. He has implemented various AWS works (integration, price optimization, and high availability), automation setup, and orchestration. Ilya has a lot of experience in Travel and Finance industry, has been working independently in distributed teams, cares about business goals and a fan of a startup culture.

SKILLS

ci/cd kubernetes aws golang python c/c++ postgres redis aerospike
and the second s
ansible prometheus c10k problem udp/tcp elasticsearch
terraform docker grpc

WORK EXPERIENCE (6)

Software Engineer at Toptal November 2018- Current

As a Toptal engineer I was working for different clients, assisting in their challenges. Technologies: Golang, Python, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Logbeats, Metricbeat, Heartbeat, Wazuh, AWS, Docker, gRPC, Kubernetes

- Designed and integrated metrics system
- Added GPU support for golang TensorFlow library in kubernetes
- Moved functionality from NodeJS monolith to GoLang microservices
- Created a number of microservices from scratch

Software Developer at Coins.ph December 2017- October 2018

Coins.ph is a digital wallet that Filipinos can use to make payments or buy digital currency such as Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, and Ethereum. As a Software Developer, I was a part of the infrastructure team. Technologies: Python, Django, Celery, Golang, SQS, SNS, Tornado, Beego, Mockgen, Ginkgo, AWS, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Redis

- Implemented a decorator to make any django view asynchronous
- Designed and implemented Jira/Github/Cl/Deployment integration service
- Alphapoint exchange integrated, providing the customers with an inexpensive way to exchange fiat and crypto-currencies
- Golang micro-service template designed
- Integrated Prometheus monitoring to Kubernetes cluster and the apps running in it
- Redis cluster autoscaling for Kubernetes

Software Engineer at Gett.com February 2017- December 2017

Gett is a taxi app, like Uber, that's most popular in Russia and Israel. As a part of a Billing Team, I was responsible for delivering internal accounting service for drivers and passengers. Techhologies: Golang, Ruby, PostgreSQL, SQS, SNS, API Gateway

- Prepared the team to pass an internal qualification test based on Go
- Crafted the architecture of the driver earnings service (DES) with an embedded conflict resolution system
- Developed an API for the business intelligence in the driver earnings service (DES)
- Profiled and resolved the major performance issue in the DES production

System Architect at Emerging Travel Inc. (ETI) February 2015- October 2016

Active engagement in the development of middle and long-term tech strategy. Maintaining high availability of a project. Research and development of scalable project architecture. Splitting monolith code blocks into individual services. Providing developer teams with convenient tools and services for every-day tasks. Resolving technical questions with partners. Technologies: Golang, Python, Protobuf, AWS, TCP, API Gateway, Aerospike, Kafka

- Designed and led the development of third-parties integrations pipeline
- Designed and integrated micro-service architecture on top of Kubernetes
- Built the network balancing layer

Software Engineer at Emerging Travel Inc. (ETI) October 2011- February 2015

Website search system speed and quality improvements. Technologies: Golang, Python, Protobuf, AWS, TCP, API Gateway, Aerospike, Kafka

- Designed and implemented dynamic pricing engine (based on marketing, supply, and customer properties)
- Designed and implemented business rules engine
- Split monolith python code to Golang/Python microservices
- Created 1Tb/1,000,000rps caching layer, based on Aerospike cluster

Software Developer at Mail.Ru Group February 2010- October 2011

- ICQ (AOL) acceptance tests (when it was bought by the Mail.RU Group)
- Developed the ICQ-to-Mail.Ru Agent interservice communication (interop)

EDUCATION (2)

Bachelor of Science Computer Science at Colegio De Porta Vaga **2014 - 2018**

Bachelor of Science Applied Mathematics at Moscow Institue of Physics and Technology (MIPT) **2005 - 2009**

PUBLICATIONS

Rapid Web Development. Golang vs Ruby in Sphere Inc 28 October 2017

1,000,000 concurrent data streams in Avito Tech 28 October 2017

Golang strengths and weakness for startup in Yandex Tech talks 20 November 2013

Building a distributed cache system in PyCon Russia 2013 **24 February 2013**